

Vikram Deshmukh

San Jose, CA 95126 +1 (669) 265-9931 vikram.deshmukh@sjsu.edu

Profile

Front-end Developer with over 9 years of experience in developing Web 2.0 applications for the desktop as well as mobile web with a keen eye for UX.

Avid technology enthusiast; gadget freak; old school PC gamer; I love creating Data Visualizations and developing Apps (for both Mobile & Web), travelling and occasionally reading good fiction.

Skill Set

JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, underscoreJS, D3.js

Data Visualizations & Web Apps

Java, Android, Swift for iOS

Responsive Web Dev, Twitter Bootstrap

• HTML5, CSS3

Wireframing, Prototyping, UML Modelling, Design Patterns

Work Experience 9 years 1 month

Senior Developer (remote) at tPoint Solutions, Maidenhead, England May 2014 - July 2016
Led entire front-end development effort of the company. Working on a low-latency Performance Monitoring Data Visualization Dashboard that is completely responsive.

UI Engineer at ZyFin Research Private Limited, Mumbai, India *Peptember 2012 - May 2014*Designed and developed cross-browser, cross-platform Web Apps and Data Visualizations using macroeconomic data and HTML5, CSS3, ¡Query, and D3.

IT Analyst at Jean Martin Systems India Limited, Chennai, India September 2012

Worked with the on-site development team in building a clean energy setup monitoring dashboard for Petra Solar (one of the industry leaders in solar-energy business in the US).

IT Analyst at TATA Consultancy Services, Mumbai, India *y 2011 - January 2012*Developed Cubbuzz (an interactive advertising-cum-marketing tool with tracking capabilities for analytics) for AXA Equitable and ING Direct. I was awarded a certificate for my outstanding contribution.

Senior Software Engineer at Geodesic, Mumbai, India *Ily 2009 - July 2011*As Senior Software Engineer, developed indigenous trading and Portfolio Analytics application for Angel Broking.

As Software Engineer, created a comprehensive Wealth Management Application (desktop and online version).

Senior Programmer at Zeus Learning, Mumbai, India 2007 – July 2009

As Senior Programmer, led a team (of 3 Programmers + 1 tester) on a large-scale in-house project. Organized recruitment drives, set aptitude test papers and conducted interviews for the employer.

As Web Programmer, underwent training in Web Dev technologies & started working on a prestigious project for Discovery Education within a month of training.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science

San Jose State University, San Jose, CA, USA

· CS218: Cloud Computing · CS251A Obj Oriented Analysis · CS175-02 Mobile Device Dev

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, MH, India